

jenny.ma2205@gmail.com | 917-521-9165 | Whitestone, NY 11357

Summary

Tech-savvy and smart medical receptionist equipped with experience in medical environments and top-notch administrative skills. Works great with colleagues and maintains strong patient relations. Excels at following procedures and independently handling common questions and concerns.

Skills

- Scheduling and calendar management
- Training and coaching
- Invoicing and billing
- File and data retrieval systems

- Office administration
- Electronic medical records (EMR) systems
- Data entry
- Expert in Word, Excel, Powerpoint, etc.

Experience

Northwell | Fresh Meadows, NY Office Admin

12/2020 - Current

- Organized and maintained filing and document management systems by coordinating, archiving and purging files.
- Developed administrative processes to achieve organizational objectives and improve office efficiency.
- Directed customer communication to appropriate department personnel.
- Handled payment processing and provided customers with receipts and proper bills and change.
- Welcomed patrons to front desk and engaged in friendly conversations while conducting check-in process.
- Prepared daily shift close reports and balanced cash register to accurately reflect all transactions.
- Reviewed safety, health and sanitation processes throughout areas and enforced rules to promote security and safety.
- Entered insurance, demographics and health history into patient database.
- Protected patients by observing strict HIPAA guidelines.
- Trained new staff on office procedures, insurance processes and medical terminology.
- Retrieved faxes and uploaded documents to patient charts to assist clinical
- Carried out daily tasks by professionally communicating with physicians, nursing staff, technicians and medical assistants.
- Arranged new merchandise with signage and appealing displays to encourage customer sales and move overstock items.
- Sold various products by explaining unique features and educating customers on proper application.
- Built and maintained relationships with peers and upper management to drive team success.
- Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines,

Macy's | Flushing, NY **Sales Associate** 06/2019 - 12/2020

payment policies and security practices.

- Assisted teammates with sales-processing tasks to meet daily sales goals.
- Retained product, service and company policy knowledge to serve as resource for both coworkers and customers.
- Built trusting relationships with customers by making personal connections.
- Coordinated activities with other departments to ensure quality customer
- Met merchandise processing standards and maintained organized and accessible work area.

Wellsure Medical Practice | Flushing, NY Front Desk Receptionist 10/2018 - 09/2020

- Handled payment processing and provided customers with receipts and proper bills and change.
- Welcomed patrons to front desk and engaged in friendly conversations while conducting check-in process.
- Prepared daily shift close reports and balanced cash register to accurately reflect all transactions.
- Entered insurance, demographics and health history into patient database.
- Called patients to confirm scheduled appointments and obtain additional details.
- Checked patients in and out for appointments and collected co-payments.
- Scheduled and followed up on patient appointments, collected and processed patient payments and maintained patient files.
- Processed patient payments and scanned identification and insurance cards.
- Protected patients by observing strict HIPAA guidelines.
- Answered multi-line phone system and directed callers to requested personnel and departments.
- Greeted each patient pleasantly and offered desk sheet for easy sign-in.
- Informed patients of financial responsibilities prior to rendering services.
- Managed office phone lines by checking voicemail, returning calls and directing messages to team members.
- Followed infection control procedures to protect patients and staff in waiting area.

NY

Volunteer Clerical Assistant 06/2016 - 08/2017

- New York Presbyterian Queens | Flushing, Relayed messages from patients to physicians about concerns, condition updates or refill requests to facilitate treatment.
 - Scheduled appointments for patients via phone and in person.
 - Prepared treatment rooms for patients by cleaning surfaces and restocking supplies.
 - Maintained inventory, vaccination and product expiration logs to record updated documentation for tracking purposes.
 - Assessed, documented and monitored vital signs for patients within outpatient setting.
 - Called patients to confirm scheduled appointments and obtain additional details.
 - Scheduled and followed up on patient appointments, collected and processed patient payments and maintained patient files.

Education and Training

08/2018

Some College (N	o Degree) in Liberal Arts A	And Sciences	
Languages –			
Chinese (Manda	in):		

Queensborough Community College of The City University of New York | Oakland Gardens, NY

Native/ Bilingual